Over the years that I've been making videos, I've visited quite a few strange elevators and lifts.
제가 비디오를 만들어온 수년 동안, 꽤 많은 이상한 엘리베이터와 승강기들을 방문했습니다.
And every time I do, I get emails from people in Germany, saying "what about the one in the New Town Hall in Hanover?"
그리고 그럴 때마다, 독일 사람들로부터 "하노버 신시청사에 있는 엘리베이터는 어떻게 생각하세요?"라는 이메일을 받습니다.
And look, I don't want to become 'that weird elevator guy', but... I finally made it.
이봐요, 저는 '그 이상한 엘리베이터 남자'가 되고 싶지는 않지만... 드디어 가게 되었습니다.
This New Town Hall is the only one in the whole of Germany with a dome.
이 신시청사는 독일 전체에서 돔을 가진 유일한 건물입니다.
That's the first specialty, and another one is, of course, our curved elevator.
그것이 첫 번째 특징이고, 또 다른 특징은 물론 우리의 곡선형 엘리베이터입니다.
That's the only one in the world.
그것은 세계에서 유일한 것입니다.
The elevator was opened in 1913, at the same time as this building was finished.
이 엘리베이터는 1913년, 이 건물이 완공됨과 동시에 개통되었습니다.
They didn't want to change the design of this building, otherwise they had to install this elevator just in the middle of the main hall.
그들은 이 건물의 디자인을 변경하고 싶지 않았고, 그렇지 않으면 메인 홀 한가운데에 엘리베이터를 설치해야 했습니다.
So they found one spot on this building, one small tower, and the elevator follows the form of the cupola.
그래서 그들은 이 건물의 한 지점, 작은 탑 하나를 찾았고, 엘리베이터는 돔의 형태를 따라갑니다.
It starts in the third floor of this building, 42 meters high, 8.3 meters sideways.
이 건물의 3층에서 시작해서, 높이 42미터, 옆으로 8.3미터입니다.
This elevator technik was developed during the construction of this building.
이 엘리베이터 기술은 이 건물의 건설 중에 개발되었습니다.
Elevators were already fairly common in high buildings by the time this was constructed, but this elevator has a unique design requirement.
이것이 건설될 당시 엘리베이터는 이미 고층 건물에서 꽤 일반적이었지만, 이 엘리베이터는 독특한 설계 요구사항을 가지고 있습니다.
It means to travel up the side of a dome.
돔의 측면을 따라 올라가야 한다는 것입니다.
The whole elevator shaft is curved.
전체 엘리베이터 샤프트가 곡선입니다.
It's not a diagonal straight line like the Eiffel Tower lifts.
에펠탑 승강기처럼 대각선 직선이 아닙니다.
The track bends as it goes up, about 17°.
트랙이 올라가면서 약 17도 정도 구부러집니다.
And it doesn't bend evenly. It's not a smooth curve.
그리고 고르게 구부러지지 않습니다. 부드러운 곡선이 아닙니다.
The path the elevator takes is irregular and lumpy.
엘리베이터가 따라가는 경로는 불규칙하고 울퉁불퉁합니다.
That would be a design challenge today, let alone a century ago.
그것은 오늘날에도 설계상의 도전이 될 것인데, 하물며 100년 전에는 말할 것도 없겠죠.
The new elevator was built by the company Lutz from Hamburg.
새로운 엘리베이터는 함부르크의 루츠 회사에서 제작되었습니다.
You cannot use this elevator the whole year, because in the winter it's very slippery there on the dome.
겨울에는 돔 위가 매우 미끄럽기 때문에 일 년 내내 이 엘리베이터를 사용할 수는 없습니다.
So each spring, there are many Hanover people who cannot wait to see again Hanover from above.
그래서 매년 봄마다, 하노버를 다시 위에서 내려다보고 싶어서 기다릴 수 없는 많은 하노버 사람들이 있습니다.
The various parts and mechanisms of the original lift were replaced over the years, and in 2007, what was left was ripped out.
원래 승강기의 다양한 부품과 메커니즘들이 수년에 걸쳐 교체되었고, 2007년에 남은 것들이 철거되었습니다.
A few months later, this brand new elevator was completed.
몇 달 후, 이 완전히 새로운 엘리베이터가 완성되었습니다.
And it only just fits.
그리고 간신히 들어맞습니다.
At points, there's only 5mm of clearance between the cabin and the wall.
어떤 지점에서는 캐빈과 벽 사이에 단 5mm의 여유 공간만 있습니다.
At other places, there's lots more.
다른 곳에서는 훨씬 더 많은 공간이 있습니다.
Apparently, during testing and construction, it did bump and scrape the walls sometimes.
테스트와 건설 중에는 실제로 때때로 벽에 부딪히고 긁혔다고 합니다.
Like I said, the path is lumpy.
제가 말했듯이, 경로가 울퉁불퉁합니다.
Oh, and also, the floor panels of this new lift? They can be transparent.
아, 그리고 또한, 이 새로운 승강기의 바닥 패널들은 투명하게 만들 수 있습니다.
Obvious question: how do they keep the cabin vertical as it goes up?
당연한 질문: 올라가면서 캐빈을 어떻게 수직으로 유지하나요?
I assumed this would have some kind of clever self-levelling mechanism, like a funicular railway, or the tram at Gateway Arch in St Louis.
저는 이것이 케이블카나 세인트루이스 게이트웨이 아치의 트램처럼 어떤 종류의 영리한 자동 수평 메커니즘을 가지고 있을 것이라고 생각했습니다.
Or maybe a floor with hydraulics in it, so it would stay level as the cabin moved around it.
아니면 유압 장치가 있는 바닥이 있어서 캐빈이 움직여도 수평을 유지할 수 있을 것이라고 생각했습니다.
But no. The solution is simple. They don't keep the floor level!
하지만 아닙니다. 해결책은 간단합니다. 바닥을 수평으로 유지하지 않습니다!
The whole cabin is just dragged up the side as one.
전체 캐빈이 그냥 하나로 측면을 따라 끌려 올라갑니다.
I can't lean on these doors, but I want to.
이 문들에 기댈 수는 없지만, 기대고 싶습니다.
I'm leaning on this pole.
저는 이 기둥에 기대고 있습니다.
We started out on the ground at a slight angle, passed through vertical about halfway up, and we ended up leaning a little bit the other way.
우리는 지상에서 약간 기울어진 상태로 시작해서, 중간쯤에서 수직을 지나고, 마지막에는 다른 쪽으로 약간 기울어진 상태로 끝났습니다.
Because a floor with a tilt of a few degrees isn't really a big problem for a short journey.
몇 도 기울어진 바닥은 짧은 여행에서는 실제로 큰 문제가 되지 않기 때문입니다.
So there you go. Germany, you can stop emailing me.
자, 여기까지입니다. 독일 여러분, 이제 이메일 보내는 것을 멈춰도 됩니다.
I have finally taken a trip on your elevator.
저는 드디어 당신들의 엘리베이터를 타봤습니다.
For a video about an elevator ride, that was a lot of steps.
엘리베이터 타기에 관한 비디오치고는 정말 많은 계단이 있었네요.